<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

  <properties>
    <title>Page Title</title>
    <!--  <author email="user@company.com">John Doe</author> -->
  </properties>

  <!-- Optional HEAD element, which is copied as is into the XHTML <head> element -->
  <!--
  <head>
    <meta ... />
  </head>
  -->

  <body>

    <!-- The body of the document contains a number of sections -->
    <section name="Case Study">

		<div class="slide">
		
			<div class="twoColumn">
				
				<h2>How Does it Work in Practice?</h2>
				
				<p>The following diagram shows the graph produced by Sanity4J 
				for a DIAC Portal Development Project. The project began by creating
				code quickly, with little regard for quality (green line). Sanity4J 
				reports were configured for the project and an 85% quality target 
				was set. Developers began to improve code quality by fixing issues 
				as the project progressed. Towards the go-live date, the team was 
				advised that their code would be subjected to an external review. 
				This caused an increased focus on quality which Sanity4J tracked.</p>
				
				<div class="imgHolder">
					<img src="images/caseStudy.png" alt="example graph"/>
				</div>
				
				<p>The external code review pointed out that the project had failed 
				to reach Departmental targets for automated unit tests, represented 
				by the red and blue lines. Prior to go-live, the project was able to 
				dramatically increase their level of automated unit testing and their 
				progress was tracked by Sanity4J.</p>
				
				<p><strong>The result was a higher quality product, which is estimated
				to cost much less to maintain in future years.</strong></p>
				
				<h3>Monitoring Progress</h3>
				
				<p>The information that Sanity4J tracks was available to developers, 
				project staff and the project executive throughout the development
				of the project. Sanity4J provided the ability to easily measure and 
				track quality. It is unlikely that the project would have achieved 
				such significant improvements without support from Sanity4J.</p>
				
			</div>
			
		</div>

    </section>

  </body>

</document>